{
    "quizzes": [
        {
            "quizId": "astronomy_easy",
            "subject": "Astronomy",
            "difficulty": "easy",
            "quizName": "Astronomy Easy Quiz",
            "quizQuestions": [{
                "question": "What is the closest planet to the Sun?",
                "answers": ["Venus","Saturn","Mars","Mercury"],
                "rightAnswer": "Mercury",
                "id": "QSTN_001_E_ASTR"
            },
            {
                "question": "How many moons does Earth have?",
                "answers": [1, 2, 3, 0],
                "rightAnswer": 2,
                "id": "QSTN_002_E_ASTR"
            },{
                "question": "What inspired our naming of the Solar System planets?",
                "answers": ["Greek mythology", "Roman mythology", "Celtic mythology", "Sumerian mythology"],
                "rightAnswer": "Roman mythology",
                "id": "QSTN_003_E_ASTR"
            },{
                "question": "How many moons does Jupiter have?",
                "answers": [95, 100, 9, 27],
                "rightAnswer": 95,
                "id": "QSTN_004_E_ASTR"
            },{
                "question": "What is the largest type of star in the universe?",
                "answers": ["White Dwarf","Red Supergiant", "Neutron Star", "Yellow Dwarf"],
                "rightAnswer": "Red Supergiant",
                "id": "QSTN_005_E_ASTR"
            },{
                "question": "What is the main component of the Sun?",
                "answers": ["Helium","Oxygen", "Carbon", "Hydrogen"],
                "rightAnswer": "Hydrogen",
                "id": "QSTN_006_E_ASTR"
            },{
                "question": "Which planet has a day that lasts longer than its year?",
                "answers": ["Mercury","Venus", "Earth", "Mars"],
                "rightAnswer": "Venus",
                "id": "QSTN_007_E_ASTR"
            }
            ]
        },
        {
            "quizId": "astronomy_difficult",
            "subject": "Astronomy",
            "difficulty": "difficult",
            "quizName": "Astronomy Difficult Quiz",
            "quizQuestions": [
                {
                    "question": "What is the estimated age of the universe according to the Big Bang theory?",
                    "answers": ["4.5 billion years","10.8 billion years","13.8 billion years","20.5 billion years"],
                    "rightAnswer": "13.8 billion years",
                    "id": "QSTN_001_D_ASTR"
                },
                {
                    "question": "Which element is produced during the triple-alpha process in stellar nucleosynthesis?",
                    "answers": ["Helium", "Carbon", "Oxygen", "Iron"],
                    "rightAnswer": "Carbon",
                    "id": "QSTN_002_D_ASTR"
                },{
                    "question": "Which of the following is the name of the largest known structure in the observable universe?",
                    "answers": ["The Hercules-Corona Borealis Great Wall", "The Virgo Supercluster", "The Local Group", "The Sloan Great Wall"],
                    "rightAnswer": "The Hercules-Corona Borealis Great Wall",
                    "id": "QSTN_003_D_ASTR"
                },{
                    "question": "What is the term for the point in a planet's orbit when it is farthest from the Sun?",
                    "answers": ["Perihelion", "Aphelion", "Equinox", "Zenith"],
                    "rightAnswer": "Aphelion",
                    "id": "QSTN_004_D_ASTR"
                },{
                    "question": "Which spacecraft was the first to pass through the asteroid belt and reach Jupiter?",
                    "answers": ["Pioneer 10","Voyager 1", "New Horizons", "Galileo"],
                    "rightAnswer": "Pioneer 10",
                    "id": "QSTN_005_D_ASTR"
                },{
                    "question": "What is the critical density of the universe associated with?",
                    "answers": ["The amount of dark energy required to sustain expansion","The mass density that determines the geometry of the universe", "The energy produced in a quasar", "The mass of neutron stars"],
                    "rightAnswer": "The mass density that determines the geometry of the universe",
                    "id": "QSTN_006_D_ASTR"
                },{
                    "question": "What is the term for the phenomenon when a planet or moon has the same rotational period as its orbital period, showing only one face to the object it orbits?",
                    "answers": ["Tidal locking","Retrograde motion", "Eccentricity", "Opposition"],
                    "rightAnswer": "Tidal locking",
                    "id": "QSTN_007_D_ASTR"
                }
                ]
        },
        {
            "quizId": "botany_easy",
            "subject": "Botany",
            "difficulty": "easy",
            "quizName": "Botany Easy Quiz",
            "quizQuestions": [
                {
                    "question": "Which part of a plant is responsible for photosynthesis?",
                    "answers": ["Roots","Flowers","Leaves","Stems"],
                    "rightAnswer": "Leaves",
                    "id": "QSTN_001_E_BOTN"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the process by which plants lose water vapor from their leaves?",
                    "answers": ["Transpiration", "Photosynthesis", "Respiration", "Germination"],
                    "rightAnswer": "Transpiration",
                    "id": "QSTN_002_E_BOTN"
                },{
                    "question": "What is the main purpose of a plantâ€™s flowers?",
                    "answers": ["To attract insects", "To support leaves", "Reproduction", "Water storage"],
                    "rightAnswer": "Reproduction",
                    "id": "QSTN_003_E_BOTN"
                },{
                    "question": "Which of the following plants is a gymnosperm?",
                    "answers": ["Pine Tree", "Rose", "Apple Tree", "Fern"],
                    "rightAnswer": "Pine Tree",
                    "id": "QSTN_004_E_BOTN"
                },{
                    "question": "What is the scientific term for the arrangement of leaves on a stem?",
                    "answers": ["Phyllotaxy","Chloroplast", "Stomata", "Germination"],
                    "rightAnswer": "Phyllotaxy",
                    "id": "QSTN_005_E_BOTN"
                },{
                    "question": "Which gas do plants absorb during photosynthesis?",
                    "answers": ["Nitrogen","Oxygen", "Carbon Dioxide", "Hydrogen"],
                    "rightAnswer": "Carbon Dioxide",
                    "id": "QSTN_006_E_BOTN"
                },{
                    "question": "What is the scientific (Latin) name of the common sunflower?",
                    "answers": ["Rosa canina","Helianthus annuus", "Quercus robur", "Ficus elastica"],
                    "rightAnswer": "Helianthus annuus",
                    "id": "QSTN_007_E_BOTN"
                }
                ]
        },
        {
            "quizId": "botany_difficult",
            "subject": "Botany",
            "difficulty": "difficult",
            "quizName": "Botany Difficult Quiz",
            "quizQuestions": [
                {
                    "question": "What is the primary reason C4 plants are more efficient in hot climates than C3 plants?",
                    "answers": ["Better water retention","More efficient CO2 fixation at high temperatures","Resistance to UV radiation","Faster growth rates"],
                    "rightAnswer": "More efficient CO2 fixation at high temperatures",
                    "id": "QSTN_001_D_BOTN"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What type of plant tissue is responsible for transporting water and nutrients from the roots to the leaves?",
                    "answers": ["Phloem", "Xylem", "Cambium", "Cortex"],
                    "rightAnswer": "Xylem",
                    "id": "QSTN_002_D_BOTN"
                },{
                    "question": "Which plant hormone is primarily responsible for fruit ripening?",
                    "answers": ["Auxin", "Cytokinin", "Ethylene", "Gibberellin"],
                    "rightAnswer": "Ethylene",
                    "id": "QSTN_003_D_BOTN"
                },{
                    "question": "What is the scientific name of the common dandelion?",
                    "answers": ["Taraxacum officinale", "Bellis perennis", "Echinacea purpurea", "Matricaria chamomilla"],
                    "rightAnswer": "Taraxacum officinale",
                    "id": "QSTN_004_D_BOTN"
                },{
                    "question": "In which part of a flower is the ovule found?",
                    "answers": ["Stigma","Anther", "Ovary", "Filament"],
                    "rightAnswer": "Ovary",
                    "id": "QSTN_005_D_BOTN"
                },{
                    "question": "Which type of plastid is primarily responsible for storing starch in plants?",
                    "answers": ["Chloroplast","Chromoplast", "Amyloplast", "Leucoplast"],
                    "rightAnswer": "Amyloplast",
                    "id": "QSTN_006_D_BOTN"
                },{
                    "question": "Which plant family does the coffee plant (Coffea arabica) belong to?",
                    "answers": ["Fabaceae","Solanaceae", "Rubiaceae", "Asteraceae"],
                    "rightAnswer": "Rubiaceae",
                    "id": "QSTN_007_D_BOTN"
                }
                ]
        },
        {
            "quizId": "neuroscience_easy",
            "subject": "Neuroscience",
            "difficulty": "easy",
            "quizName": "Neuroscience Easy Quiz",
            "quizQuestions": [
                {
                    "question": "What is the primary neurotransmitter involved in muscle movement?",
                    "answers": ["Dopamine","Serotonin","Acetylcholine","Glutamate"],
                    "rightAnswer": "Acetylcholine",
                    "id": "QSTN_001_E_NEUR"
                },
                {
                    "question": "Which part of the brain is responsible for regulating balance and coordination?",
                    "answers": ["Cerebellum", "Hippocampus", "Amygdala", "Thalamus"],
                    "rightAnswer": "Cerebellum",
                    "id": "QSTN_002_E_NEUR"
                },{
                    "question": "Which brain region is primarily involved in the formation of long-term memory?",
                    "answers": ["Frontal Lobe", "Hypothalamus", "Hippocampus", "Occipital Lobe"],
                    "rightAnswer": "Hippocampus",
                    "id": "QSTN_003_E_NEUR"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What type of cells in the nervous system are responsible for supporting neurons?",
                    "answers": ["Neurons","Axons", "Glial Cells", "Dendrites"],
                    "rightAnswer": "Glial Cells",
                    "id": "QSTN_004_E_NEUR"
                },{
                    "question": "What is the blood-brain barrier primarily responsible for?",
                    "answers": ["Circulating blood through the brain","Protecting the brain from harmful substances", "Generating neural impulses", "Absorbing nutrients into the brain"],
                    "rightAnswer": "Protecting the brain from harmful substances",
                    "id": "QSTN_005_E_NEUR"
                },{
                    "question": "Which of the following is a neurotransmitter primarily associated with feelings of pleasure and reward?",
                    "answers": ["Serotonin","Dopamine", "Norepinephrine", "GABA"],
                    "rightAnswer": "Dopamine",
                    "id": "QSTN_006_E_NEUR"
                },{
                    "question": "What is the main function of myelin in the nervous system?",
                    "answers": ["Generating electrical signals","Increasing the speed of signal transmission", "Storing memories", "Absorbing nutrients for neurons"],
                    "rightAnswer": "Increasing the speed of signal transmission",
                    "id": "QSTN_007_E_NEUR"
                }
                ]
        },
        {
            "quizId": "neuroscience_difficult",
            "subject": "Neuroscience",
            "difficulty": "difficult",
            "quizName": "Neuroscience Difficult Quiz",
            "quizQuestions": [
                {
                    "question": "Which neurotransmitter is primarily involved in the brain's reward system and addiction mechanisms?",
                    "answers": ["Dopamine","Serotonin","GABA","Glutamate"],
                    "rightAnswer": "Dopamine",
                    "id": "QSTN_001_D_NEUR"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the primary role of the basal ganglia in the brain?",
                    "answers": ["Regulating emotions", "Coordinating voluntary movements", "Processing sensory input", "Regulating body temperature"],
                    "rightAnswer": "Coordinating voluntary movements",
                    "id": "QSTN_002_D_NEUR"
                },{
                    "question": "Which type of glial cell is involved in the formation of the blood-brain barrier?",
                    "answers": ["Oligodendrocytes", "Astrocytes", "Microglia", "Schwann cells"],
                    "rightAnswer": "Astrocytes",
                    "id": "QSTN_003_D_NEUR"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the main function of the corpus callosum?",
                    "answers": ["Connects the two hemispheres of the brain","Processes auditory information", "Controls autonomic functions", "Produces cerebrospinal fluid"],
                    "rightAnswer": "Connects the two hemispheres of the brain",
                    "id": "QSTN_004_D_NEUR"
                },{
                    "question": "Which brain wave is typically associated with deep sleep stages?",
                    "answers": ["Alpha waves","Theta waves", "Beta waves", "Delta waves"],
                    "rightAnswer": "Delta waves",
                    "id": "QSTN_005_D_NEUR"
                },{
                    "question": "What is the primary function of the substantia nigra in the brain?",
                    "answers": ["Regulates visual processing","Involved in the production of dopamine for motor control", "Coordinates speech and language", "Processes olfactory information"],
                    "rightAnswer": "Involved in the production of dopamine for motor control",
                    "id": "QSTN_006_D_NEUR"
                },{
                    "question": "Which ion is critical for the release of neurotransmitters at synaptic terminals?",
                    "answers": ["Potassium (K+)","Sodium (Na+)", "Calcium (Ca2+)", "Chloride (Cl-)"],
                    "rightAnswer": "Calcium (Ca2+)",
                    "id": "QSTN_007_D_NEUR"
                }
                ]
        }
    ]
}
